A Guide to the Commonwealth Fund records, Accession 2003:033, SG 2 FA777
Rockefeller Archive Center
Commonwealth Fund records, Accession 2003:033, SG 2
1996-2002
Rockefeller Archive Center
Commonwealth Fund
FA777
12.54 Cubic Feet 33 document boxes, Boxes 1-33.
Conditions Governing Access
Open for research with select materials restricted as noted. Brittle or damaged items are available at the discretion of RAC. Researchers interested in accessing digital media (floppy disks, CDs, DVDs, etc.) or audiovisual material (audio cassettes, VHS, etc.) in this collection must use an access surrogate. The original items may not be accessed because of preservation concerns. To request an access surrogate be made, or if you are unsure if there is an access surrogate, please contact an archivist.
Arrangement
Arranged in three series: 1. Communications. 2. IHP. 3. Quality of Care for Underserved Populations / Grants.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
The Commonwealth Fund records were donated to RAC in 1985. Record transfers began in 1986, and accruals continue.
Scope and Contents
Contains publications, grant records, documentation of surveys and symposia, as well as materials pertaining to Harkness Fellowships.
- Commonwealth Fund records, 1996-2002; 2003:033; 12.54 Cubic Feet
  - Communications, 1; 2.28 Cubic Feet
    - Publications - Commonwealth Fund Annual Report 2001 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Publications - Commonwealth Fund Quarterly 2002 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Publicaitons - Task Force on Academic Health Centers, 2002 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Publications - Health Care in New York City, 2002 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Publications - Child Development and Preventive Care, 2002 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Publications - Child Development and Preventive Care, 2002 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Publications - Quality of Care for Underserved Populations (Minority Health), 2002 (Box 2, Folder 7-8)
    - Publications - Health Care Quality Improvement, 2002 (Box 2, Folder 9-10)
    - Publications - Picker-Commonwealth Fund Program on Quality of Care for Frail Elders (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - Publications - Task Force on Future of Health Insurance, 2002 (Box 3, Folder 12-15)
    - Publications - Program on Medicare's Future, 2002 (Box 3, Folder 16-17)
    - Publications - Program on Medicare's Future, 2002 (Box 4, Folder 18-20)
    - Publications - Annual Report Photos, 1995-2001 (Box 4, Folder 21-27)
    - Publications - Historical Photos, 1930s; 4 prints and corresponding negatives. (Box 4, Item 2003:033:001)
      Conditions Governing Access
      The images have been physically separated from the body of the collection to facilitate stabilization and long-term preservation. Each item is assigned a unique separation number, as noted. Requests to access open special formats should reference the unique separation number.
      Scope and Contents
      Edward and Mary Harkness (Court of St. James), Charlotte Stillman, Mary Harkness and Group at Yeamans Hall (1935).
    - Media Clippings on Fund Programs, 2001-2002 (Box 5, Folder 28-32)
    - Media Clippings on Fund Programs, 2002 (Box 6, Folder 33)
  - IHP, 2; 7.6 Cubic Feet
    - Harkness Fellows - 2000-2001 - Heather Wilkinson, 1999 (Box 6, Folder 34)
    - Harkness Fellows - 2000-2001 - Nicholas McNulty, 1999 (Box 6, Folder 35)
    - Harkness Fellows - 2000-2001 - Jacqueline Paige, 1999 (Box 6, Folder 36)
    - Harkness Fellows - 2000-2001 - Andrew Reed, 1999 (Box 6, Folder 37)
    - Harkness Fellows - 2000-2001 - Application Requests Letters, 1999 (Box 6, Folder 38-39)
    - Harkness Fellows - 2000-2001 - Applications Sent, 1999 (Box 7, Folder 40-41)
    - Harkness Fellows - 2000-2001 - Nominators, 1999 (Box 7, Folder 42-43)
    - Harkness Fellows - 2000-2001 - Nominator Letters, 1999 (Box 7, Folder 44)
    - Harkness Fellows - 2000-2001 - Nominator Letters, 1999 (Box 8, Folder 45-49)
    - Harkness Fellows - 2000-2001 - Nominator Letters, 1999 (Box 9, Folder 50)
    - Harkness Fellows - Applicants - Stephen Payton - Ministry of Foreign Affairs and Trade (HF 00-011 NZ), 1999 (Box 9, Folder 51)
    - Harkness Fellows - Applicants - Kay Pattison - Department of Health (HF 00-036 UK), 1999 (Box 9, Folder 52)
    - Harkness Fellows - Applicants - Michael G. Baker - ESR-Wellington School of Medicine (HF 00-015 NZ), 1999 (Box 9, Folder 53)
    - Harkness Fellows - Applicants - Elizabeth (Libby) A. Carr - Parliament (HF 00-016 NZ), 1999 (Box 9, Folder 54)
    - Harkness Fellows - Applicants - Tanira Kingi - Massey University (HF 00-008 NZ), 1999 (Box 9, Folder 55)
    - Harkness Fellows - Applicants - Joy Cooper - Mental Health Commission (HF 00-017 NZ), 1999 (Box 9, Folder 56)
    - Harkness Fellows - Applicants - Therese M. Egan - Ministry of Health (HF 00-019 NZ), 1999 (Box 9, Folder 57)
    - Harkness Fellows - Applicants - Karen M. Flegg - Royal New Zealand College of General Practioners (HF 00-020 NZ), 1999 (Box 9, Folder 58)
    - Harkness Fellows - Applicants - Robin D. Gauld - University of Otago (HF 00-021 NZ), 1999 (Box 9, Folder 59)
    - Harkness Fellows - Applicants - Cameron Grant - University of Aukland-Starship Children's Hospital (HF 00-022 NZ), 1999 (Box 9, Folder 60)
    - Harkness Fellows - Applicants - Peter J. Paul - Aukland Health Care Services, Ltd. (HF 00-023 NZ), 1999 (Box 10, Folder 61)
    - Harkness Fellows - Applicants - Keri H. Ratima - Te Whakatohea Maori Trust Board (HF 00-024 NZ), 1999 (Box 10, Folder 62)
    - Harkness Fellows - Applicants - Kathy Spencer - Parliament (HF 00-025 NZ), 1999 (Box 10, Folder 63)
    - Harkness Fellows - Applicants - Robyn Stent - Office of the Health and Disability Commissioner (HF 00-026 NZ), 1999 (Box 10, Folder 64)
    - Harkness Fellows - Applicants - William M. Thomson - University of Otago (HF 00-027 NZ), 1999 (Box 10, Folder 65)
    - Harkness Fellows - Applicants - John A. Waldon - Massey University (HF 00-029 NZ), 1999 (Box 10, Folder 66)
    - Harkness Fellows - Applicants - Linda (Sue) Wells - National Heart Foundation (HF 00-030 NZ), 1999 (Box 10, Folder 67)
    - Harkness Fellows - Applicants - Heather Worth - University of Aukland (HF 00-031 NZ), 1999 (Box 10, Folder 68)
    - Harkness Fellows - Applicants - Timothy Ore - UNSW (HF 00-002 AUS), 1999 (Box 10, Folder 69)
    - Harkness Fellows - Applicants - Gwendolyn Gray - ANU (HF 00-004 AUS), 1999 (Box 10, Folder 70)
    - Harkness Fellows - Applicants - Damain Mahoney - Queensland Health (HF 00-005 AUS), 1999 (Box 11, Folder 71)
    - Harkness Fellows - Applicants - Sally Gibson - Sexual Health Information and Networking, SA (HF 00-006 AUS), 1999 (Box 11, Folder 72)
    - Harkness Fellows - Applicants - Mary Almer - Northern Sydney Home Nursing Service (HF 00-007 AUS), 1999 (Box 11, Folder 73)
    - Harkness Fellows - Applicants - Ross Bailie - University of Nth Territory Clinical (HF 00-008 AUS), 1999 (Box 11, Folder 74)
    - Harkness Fellows - Applicants - John McCallum - University of Western Sydney (HF 00-009 AUS), 1999 (Box 11, Folder 75)
    - Harkness Fellows - Applicants - Mark Welch - NSW Health (HF 00-010 AUS), 1999 (Box 11, Folder 76)
    - Harkness Fellows - Applicants - Paul Mackey - Commonwealth Parlimentary Library (HF 00-011 AUS), 1999 (Box 11, Folder 77)
    - Harkness Fellows - Applicants - Glenn Nicholls - Mental Health Research Institute of VIC (HF 00-012 AUS), 1999 (Box 11, Folder 78)
    - Harkness Fellows - Applicants - Sallie-Anne Pearson - University of New Castle (HF 00-013 AUS), 1999 (Box 11, Folder 79)
    - Harkness Fellows - Applicants - Wendy Chaboyer - Griffith University (HF 00-014 AUS), 1999 (Box 11, Folder 80)
    - Harkness Fellows - Applicants - Sophie Hill - La Trobe University (HF 00-015 AUS), 1999 (Box 11, Folder 81)
    - Harkness Fellows - Applicants - Michael Fett - Department of Health and Aged Care (HF 00-016 AUS), 1999 (Box 11, Folder 82)
    - Harkness Fellows - Applicants - Anne Elizabeth McConville - North Derbyshire Health Authority (HF 00-001 UK), 1999 (Box 12, Folder 83)
    - Harkness Fellows - Applicants - Sandra Nutley - University of St. Andrews (HF 00-002 UK), 1999 (Box 12, Folder 84)
    - Harkness Fellows - Applicants - Stephen William Kendrick - National Health Service in Scotland (HF 00-003 UK), 1999 (Box 12, Folder 85)
    - Harkness Fellows - Applicants - Tom Smith - Cambridge University (HF 00-004 UK), 1999 (Box 12, Folder 86)
    - Harkness Fellows - Applicants - Helen Bowers - The Health Advisory Service (HF 00-005 UK), 1999 (Box 12, Folder 87)
    - Harkness Fellows - Applicants - Christopher McCabe - The University of Sheffield (HF 00-006 UK), 1999 (Box 12, Folder 88)
    - Harkness Fellows - Applicants - Yi Mien Koh - West Herts Health Authority (HF 00-007 UK), 1999 (Box 12, Folder 89)
    - Harkness Fellows - Applicants - Andrew Philip Jones - Caerphilly County Borough Council (HF 00-009 UK), 1999 (Box 12, Folder 90)
    - Harkness Fellows - Applicants - Mark Extworthy - London School of Economics and Political Science (HF 00-010 UK), 1999 (Box 12, Folder 91)
    - Harkness Fellows - Applicants - Emma Williamson - University of Bristol (HF 00-011 UK), 1999 (Box 13, Folder 92)
    - Harkness Fellows - Applicants - Tony Maltby - University of Birmingham (HF 00-012 UK), 1999 (Box 13, Folder 93)
    - Harkness Fellows - Applicants - Martin Paul Anderson - University of Nottingham (HF 00-013 UK), 1999 (Box 13, Folder 94)
    - Harkness Fellows - Applicants - Stephen Peckam - Oxford Brookes University (HF 00-014 UK), 1999 (Box 13, Folder 95)
    - Harkness Fellows - Applicants - Alasadair Gordon Miller - University of Bristol (HF 00-015 UK), 1999 (Box 13, Folder 96)
    - Harkness Fellows - Applicants - Johnathan Watson - Health Education Board of Scotland (HF 00-016 UK), 1999 (Box 13, Folder 97)
    - Harkness Fellows - Applicants - Elinor Mary Thompson - South and West Devon Health Authority (HF 00-017 UK), 1999 (Box 13, Folder 98)
    - Harkness Fellows - Applicants - Dombnall MacAuley - University of Ulster (HF 00-018 UK), 1999 (Box 13, Folder 99)
    - Harkness Fellows - Applicants - Catherine Guelbert - Withington Community Hospital Development (HF 00-019 UK), 1999 (Box 13, Folder 100)
    - Harkness Fellows - Applicants - Paul M. Wilson - University of York (HF 00-020 UK), 1999 (Box 14, Folder 101)
    - Harkness Fellows - Applicants - Richard Cookson - London School of Economics (HF 00-021 UK), 1999 (Box 14, Folder 102)
    - Harkness Fellows - Applicants - Katharine Jane Thomas - University of Sheffield (HF 00-022 UK), 1999 (Box 14, Folder 103)
    - Harkness Fellows - Applicants - Juliet Tizzard - Progress Educational Trust (HF 00-023 UK), 1999 (Box 14, Folder 104)
    - Harkness Fellows - Applicants - Daniel Timothy Wilson - Institute of Health Sciences (HF 00-024 UK), 1999 (Box 14, Folder 105)
    - Harkness Fellows - Applicants - Robert Anderson - University of Wales College of Medicine (HF 00-025 UK), 1999 (Box 14, Folder 106)
    - Harkness Fellows - Applicants - Judy Taylor - King's Fund (HF 00-026 UK), 1999 (Box 14, Folder 107)
    - Harkness Fellows - Applicants - Linda Jane Mckie - Glascow Caledonian University (HF 00-027 UK), 1999 (Box 14, Folder 108)
    - Harkness Fellows - Applicants - Sarah Elizabeth Ann Lowe - Office of National Statistics (HF 00-029 UK), 1999 (Box 15, Folder 109)
    - 2000 International Symposium - Participant List, 2000-2001 (Box 15, Folder 110)
    - 2000 International Symposium - Press Briefing, 2000-2001 (Box 15, Folder 111-112)
    - 2000 International Symposium - Allan Rock Talking Points, 2000-2001 (Box 15, Folder 113)
    - 2000 International Symposium - Karen Davis Talking Points, 2000-2001 (Box 15, Folder 114)
    - 2000 International Symposium - Notes, 2000-2001 (Box 15, Folder 115)
    - 2000 International Symposium - Planning Committee, 2000-2001 (Box 15, Folder 116)
    - 2000 International Symposium - St. Regis Hotel, 2000-2001 (Box 15, Folder 117)
    - 2000 International Symposium - Budget, 2000-2001 (Box 15, Folder 118)
    - 2000 International Symposium - Karen Davis Closing Remarks, 2000-2001 (Box 15, Folder 119)
    - 2000 International Symposium - Authors - Angela Coulter, 2000-2001 (Box 16, Folder 120)
    - 2000 International Symposium - Authors - Brian Hutchinson, 2000-2001 (Box 16, Folder 121)
    - 2000 International Symposium - Authors - John Eisenberg, 2000-2001 (Box 16, Folder 122)
    - 2000 International Symposium - Authors - Paul Cleary, 2000-2001 (Box 16, Folder 123)
    - 2000 International Symposium - Authors - Don Birkett, 2000-2001 (Box 16, Folder 124)
    - 2000 International Symposium - Authors - Mark Chassin, 2000-2001 (Box 16, Folder 125)
    - 2000 International Symposium - Authos - Devidas Menon, 2000-2001 (Box 16, Folder 126)
    - 2000 International Symposium - Authors - Ross Wilson, 2000-2001 (Box 16, Folder 127)
    - 2000 International Symposium - Authors - Martin Roland, 2000-2001 (Box 16, Folder 128)
    - 2000 International Symposium - Authors - Tom Noseworthy, 2000-2001 (Box 16, Folder 129)
    - 2000 International Symposium - Mark Merlis, 2000-2001 (Box 16, Folder 130)
    - 2000 International Symposium - Mark Merlis, 2000-2001 (Box 17, Folder 131-133)
    - 2000 International Symposium - Participant Correspondence - Blair House, 2000-2001 (Box 17, Folder 134)
    - 2000 International Symposium - Participant Correspondence - Thank You Letters, 2000-2001 (Box 17, Folder 135)
    - 2000 International Symposium - Participant Correspondence - General Correspondence, 2000-2001 (Box 17, Folder 136)
    - 2000 International Symposium - Participant Correspondence - Travel Letter, 2000-2001 (Box 17, Folder 137)
    - 2000 International Symposium - Participant Correspondence - Invitation Letters, 2000-2001 (Box 17, Folder 138)
    - 2000 Cross-National Comparison Data - Correspondence (990823), 1999-2000 (Box 18, Folder 139)
    - 2000 Cross-National Comparison Data - Proposal (990823), 1999-2000 (Box 18, Folder 140)
    - 2000 Cross-National Comparison Data (990823) (Box 18, Folder 141-143)
    - 2000 Health Affairs-Project Hope - Budget (990821) (Box 18, Folder 144)
    - 2000 Health Affairs-Project Hope - Correspondence (990821) (Box 18, Folder 145-146)
    - 2000 Health Affairs-Project Hope - 2002 May-June Health Affairs Issue, 1999-2002 (Box 18, Folder 147)
    - 2000 Health Affairs-Project Hope - Proposal (990821) (Box 19, Folder 148-152)
    - 2000 International Symposium - Ministers of Health - Press Briefing, 2000 September 18 (Box 28, Folder 203)
    - 2000 International Symposium - Ministers of Health - Correspondence, 20000 (Box 29, Folder 204-205)
    - 2000 International Symposium - Ministers of Health (Box 29, Folder 206-208)
    - 2000 International Symposium - Ministers of Health (Box 30, Folder 209)
    - 2000 Multinational Health Policy Survey - Correspondence (Box 30, Folder 210)
    - 2000 Multinational Health Policy Survey - Proposal (Box 30, Folder 211)
    - 2000 Multinational Health Policy Survey - Budget (Box 30, Folder 212)
    - 2000 Multinational Health Policy Survey - Banner Books (Box 30, Folder 213)
    - 2000 Multinational Health Policy Survey - Press Release (Box 30, Folder 214)
    - 2000 Multinational Health Policy Survey - Findings (Box 30, Folder 215)
    - 2000 Multinational Health Policy Survey - Charts (Box 30, Folder 216)
    - 2000 Multinational Health Policy Survey - Health Affairs Article (Box 31, Folder 217)
    - 2000 Multinational Health Policy Survey - Comments (Box 31, Folder 218)
    - 2000 Multinational Health Policy Survey - Deliverables, 1999-2000 (Box 31, Folder 219-221)
    - 1998 Multinational Survey (970926) (Box 31, Folder 222)
    - 1999 Health Affairs-Project Hope, 1999-2001 (Box 31, Folder 223)
    - 1999 Health Affairs-Project Hope, 1997-1999 (Box 32, Folder 224)
    - 1998 Health Affairs Issue, 1998-2000 (Box 32, Folder 225)
    - 1999 International Symposium Elderly Survey (Box 32, Folder 226)
    - 1999 Multinational Health Survey, 1997-2001 (Box 32, Folder 227)
    - 2000 Cross-National Comparison Data - Proposal (990823), 1999-2000 (Box 32, Folder 228)
    - 2000 Cross-National Comparison Data - Budget (990823), 2000-2001 (Box 32, Folder 229)
    - International Symposium - Chart Book Comments, 2000 (Box 32, Folder 230)
    - 2000 Cross-National Comparison Data - Correspondence (990823), 1999-2001 (Box 33, Folder 231-232)
    - 2000 Cross-National Comparison Data - P and R Deliverables (990823) (Box 33, Folder 233-234)
  - Quality of Care for Underserved Populations / Grants, 3; 3.8 Cubic Feet
    - National Committee for Quality Assurance - Improving the Collection of Quality Information in State Medicaid Programs - Jessica B. French (2000730), 2000-2002 (Box 19, Folder 153)
    - National Committee for Quality Assurance - Improving the Collection of Quality Information in State Medicaid Programs - Jessica B. French (2000730), 2000-2002 (Box 20, Folder 154-157)
    - Georgetown University Medical Center - The Impact of Managed Care and Medicaid Payment Changes on Urban Safety Net Hospitals, Phase III - Darrell J. Gaskin (990194), 1998-2002 (Box 20, Folder 158-159)
    - Georgetown University Medical Center - The Impact of Managed Care and Medicaid Payment Changes on Urban Safety Net Hospitals, Phase III - Darrell J. Gaskin (990194), 1998-2002 (Box 21, Folder 160-162)
    - Georgetown University Medical Center - The Impact of Managed Care and Medicaid Payment Changes on Urban Safety Net Hospitals, Phase II - Darrell Gaskin (970949), 1997-2000 (Box 21, Folder 163-165)
    - Georgetown University Medical Center - The Impact of Managed Care and Medicaid Payment Changes on Urban Safety Net Hospitals, Phase II - Darrell Gaskin (970949), 1997-2000 (Box 22, Folder 166)
    - George Washington University - Review of Urban Hospital and Health System Strategies - Thomas W. Chapman (970274), 1996-2000 (Box 22, Folder 167-169)
    - Jacobs Institute of Women's Health - Martha C. Romans (20000181), 1999-2002 (Box 22, Folder 170-171)
    - Jacobs Institute of Women's Health - Martha C. Romans (20010105), 2000-2002 (Box 23, Folder 172-175)
    - Jacobs Institute of Women's Health - Martha C. Romans (20010053), 2000-2002 (Box 23, Folder 176-177)
    - Jacobs Institute of Women's Health - Martha C. Romans (20010053), 2000-2002 (Box 24, Folder 178-180)
    - National Forum for Health Care Quality Measurement and Reporting - Kenneth Kizer (20010034), 1999-2002 (Box 24, Folder 181-183)
    - National Forum for Health Care Quality Measurement and Reporting - Kenneth Kizer (20010034), 1999-2002 (Box 25, Folder 184-187)
    - Summit Health Institute Research and Education - Ruth Perot (20000478), 2000-2002 (Box 25, Folder 188)
    - Summit Health Institute Research and Education - Ruth Perot (20000478), 2000-2002 (Box 26, Folder 189-192)
    - Summit Health Institute Research and Education - Ruth Perot (20000478), 2000-2002 (Box 27, Folder 193-194)
    - National Health Law Program - Jane Perkins (20010686), 2000-2002 (Box 27, Folder 195-197)
    - George Washington University - Thomas Chapman (970274), 1996-2000 (Box 28, Folder 198-202)